# **CLARANCE LIBERISTE NTWARI**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | VUE.JS & TYPESCRIPT & NODE.JS



#### **ABOUT**

RWANDA KIGALI

☐ LIBERINTWARI@GMAIL.COM

CLARANCELIBERI

✓ CLARANCELIBERI

IN/CLARANCE-LIBERISTE-NTWARI-27A484184

PROFICIENT LANGUAGES/FRAMEW ORK

#### **PROFICIENT**

TYPESCRIPT NODE.JS VUE.JS REACT.JS JAVA SPRING-BOOT GOLANG GIN

## DATABASE

#### **PROFICIENT**

REDIS MONGODB MYSQL POSTGRESQL

## OTHER LANGUAGES

## WORKING

PYTHON GOLANG JAVA

#### **DEVOPS**

#### **PROFICIENT**

DOCKER ANSIBLE JENKINS GITLAB GCP AWS

## SUMMARY

A software developer with over 4 years of experience developing modern web technologies solutions and has a passion for creativity, dedication, and ongoing personal growth. Has worked in small startups of 4 to large companies of 150 coworkers. Has led team of 10 in Agile methodologies and a track record of working remotely for 3 years, with a strong emphasis on team collaboration and efficient results

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **BRITISH PETROLEUM (BP)**

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

Delivered significant contributions to different teams, improved user experiences, managed monorepo architecture, implemented CI/CD pipelines, and helped keep track of action logs on the Superfleet platform.

- Created an audit log module that records all user actions for traceability, In audit log team.
- Created micro-frontends with Webpack module federation and Vue.js, which improved the developer experience by 70%.
- Created different components under the Atomic Design principle and Storybook while making the BP design system, reducing component dependency by 35%.
- Wrote Regression and Unit tests of the components in the BP design System.

#### **HUNTERSOFBOOK**

04/2021 - 06/2022

07/2022 - 05/2023

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

Improved frontend development and user engagement at HuntersOfBook through storybook UI components and WYSIWYG editor.

- Created Component presentation with storybook, which improved Developer experience by 15%.
- Wrote unit test and integration test respecting TDD with Jest and testinglibrary
- Built end-to-end APIs using Nest.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, and Graphql.
- Developed a powerful WYSIWYG editor using Vue.js, an editor that made content writing smooth and faster with a 45% increase in efficiency for users.
- Wrote GitHub Action scripts for PRs, automating PR validations and automatic deployment, speeding up the normal manual process from 15mins to 55 secs.

## MINISTRY OF ICT & RWANDA CODING ACADEMY

08/2021 - 07/2022

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

Led a team and implemented features at Stunnity through analysis, design, mentorship, and efficient deployment using CI/CD pipeline.

- Led software analysis and design by making Software Requirement Specification (SRS), data dictionaries, DFD, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Integrated 4 backend microservices and Frontend on Gitlab pipeline and deployment.
- Led a team of 10, Reviewed code and taught the team how to use modern software methodologies.
- Implemented different features on live streaming calls and chat with Node.js and Vue is
- Wrote component and e2e tests using the react-testing library and Cypress.

## **KURIOUS LTD**

#### PROFICIENT

AGILE SCRUM KANBAN ATOMIC DESIGN BEM

#### LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (PROFESSIONAL) KINYARWANDA (NATIVE) Developed tools for video and textual materials for students and a real-time messaging service for communication between students and teachers, improving the platform's front-end, making the platform more competitive with Coursera and Edx.

- Developed and led software analysis and design process, resulting in the successful creation of over 20 Software Requirement Specification (SRS) documents, data dictionaries, DFD diagrams, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Implemented DevOps workflows on Digital Ocean, speeding CI/CD process by 30%.
- Developed Chat, Live Stream, and Students Forum modules, resulting in a 50% increase in user engagement and communication, utilizing technologies such as webRTC, socket.io, Vue.js, and Kurento.

## **VOLUNTEER**

#### **FUTURE SKILLS BOOTCAMP**

12/2019 - 12/2019

WEB DEVELOPMENT MENTOR

Taught programming concepts to 350 children under 18 during a two week program.

- Covered five skills including HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and SQL.
- Guided and facilitated students in presenting final projects on demo day.
- Facilitated students in designing web pages within 7 days, helping to foster competitive programming and creative thinking skills.

## **EDUCATION**

## **RWANDA CODING ACADEMY**

02/2019 - 07/2022

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING & EMBEDDED SYSTEM